A Guide to the Letters of Edgar Lee Masters, 1924-1945
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters of Edgar Lee Masters, 1924-1945
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7767-h
This collection consists of 12 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased on 1989 October 27.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of a set of letters from Edgar Lee Masters. Masters writes chiefly to Ada J. McVickar re planned visits, his health, John Cowper Powys, and the possibility of McVickar selling remaining copies of "Serpents in the wilderness."
Also included is a newspaper clipping, ca. 1943, re Masters' convalescence from pneumonia and malnutrition.
Contents List
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Great Neck, New York, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1924 Feb 17, ALS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters mentions that he intends to read an article by John Cowper Powys and that he heard one of his lectures at the Plaza and was sorry to have missed the others since that one was so wonderful
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Nassau Club, Princeton, New Jersey, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1924 Apr 3, TLS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters thanks Mcvickar for the letter and article by John Cowper Powys, and indicating his wish to visit her but his dread of going to New York
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Princeton, New Jersey, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1924 Apr 12, TLS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters plans to visit McVickar, and mentioning that he tried to get in touch with both her and John Cowper Powys,
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Princeton, New Jersey, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1924 Apr 14, TLS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters invites her to visit and relaying possible plans for the day,
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, New York, New York, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York, with a newspaper article about his convalescence 1944 Mar 22, ANS. 1 p., w/env.
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, New York, New York, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1944 Mar 31, ALS. 1 p., w/env.
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Pocono Pines, Pennsylvania, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1944 Aug 17, ALS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters expresses his gratitude for [Percy Bysshe] Shelley's book Alastor(, or the Spirit of Solitude) and for her reading it to him.
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Selwyn Hotel, Charlotte, North Carolina, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1944 Dec 14, TLS. 1 p.
  Masters mentions a letter from Rev. Penfield of Yonkers, indicating that his health is improving slowly and that he hasn't returned to writing but has "themes and urges."
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Selwyn Hotel, Charlotte, North Carolina, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York 1944 Dec 20, TLS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters thanks her for the book by John Cowper Powys
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Selwyn Hotel, Charlotte, North Carolina, to Ada J. McVickar, Yonkers, New York. 1945 May 15, TLS. 1 p., w/env.
  Masters thanks her for the clipping about the Spoon River Mill, inquiring as to whether she thinks she can sell his copies of Serpents in the Wilderness, and briefly indicating that it is inconvenient to write letters too often.
- Letter from Edgar Lee Masters, Great Neck, New York, to Mr. Shaw. 1924 Jan 4, TLS. 1 p.
  Masters sends remittance for two tickets to the lecture of John Cowper Powys at the Plaza on January 8